PATRICK G. DUREZA

WEB DEVELOPER

I am a web developer with over 9 years of experience in developing web applications using various platforms and frameworks. I am hardworking, self-motivated, and dedicated to maintain industry standard knowledge and development skills. Always open and self-driven to learn new technologies & skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Frontend Developer

ZigZag Offshoring (TRIBE) / Jul 2018 - Present

react · redux · styled-components · react-admin · hubspot · scss

- develop, maintain and enhance company website
- develop, maintain and enhance company web-based platform for influencer marketing and branded content.
- develop, maintain and enhancement of web-based admin app
- participate in agile meetings (daily standups, backlog grooming, sprint retrospectives)
- perform peer code reviews

Shopify Lead Developer

Outsourced Quality Assured Services (acidgreen) / Nov 2017 – Jun 2018 shopify · liquid · react · polaris

- manage a team of Shopify developers
- develop, maintain and implement new features for high performance Shopify webstores
- develop shopify private apps
- perform code reviews

Demandware Developer

Moku Collective / Nov 2016 - Nov 2017

sfcc · demandware · iavascript · scss

- develop and maintain high performance eCommerce experience
- implement customer-centric web-based applications
- participate in daily standups

Technical Consultant/SCA Developer

Netsuite / Aug 2015 - Nov 2016

sfcc · demandware · javascript · scss

- work directly with customers to document and validate business requirements
- implement customizations to a client's NetSuite webstore
- fixing defects; investigating logs; creating enhancements and developing modules through given business rules and requirements.

SKILLS

Coding

react · redux · typescript · nextjs ·
node · express · i18n ·
react-query · use-swr · rest/hateoas ·
apollo · graphql · websockets ·
html · css · javascript · jquery ·
scss · styled-components · material-ui ·

Scripts/Build/Processors

chakra-ui · tailwindcss · ant-d ·

webpack · gulp

Testing

 $\underline{\mathsf{jest}} \cdot \underline{\mathsf{enzyme}} \cdot \underline{\mathsf{react\text{-}testing\text{-}library}} \cdot \underline{\mathsf{cypress}}$

Project/Code Management

jira · confluence · bitbucket · github · gitflow · agile · scrum

Web Platforms

firebase · heroku · vercel ·
aws · buildkite · gh-actions ·
shopify plus · hubspot · netsuite sca ·
salesforce commerce cloud

EDUCATION

Master of Information Systems

2013 - 2016 University of the Philippines OU

BS Information Technology

2006 - 2011

University of San Agustin Iloilo

WORK EXPERIENCE

Onsite Coordinator/Team Lead

Pointwest Innovations Corp (Delta Airlines) / March 2013 - Aug 2015 <u>j2ee · struts2 · jquery · scss</u>

- facilitate the offshore development team while assigned onsite (US)...
- investigate and analyze production server logs
- conducting weekly offshore meetings
- delegate tasks to team members.

Java Developer

Pointwest Innovations Corp (Delta Airlines) / Jun 2011 - Mar 2013

<u>j2ee · struts2 · jquery · scss</u>

- fix issues and defects and investigate logs.
- analyze business requirements, business rules and adhering to company coding standards

OTHER PROJECTS (Freelance work)

theaustralianbucketlist.com.au

web app for Australians to keep track of the places of interests that they would like to visit, or have already visited.

react · nexis · graphql · apollo · firebase-auth

fanlove.ph

platform for people to request personalized messages from celebrities.

 $\underline{react} \cdot \underline{redux} \cdot \underline{styled\text{-}components} \cdot \underline{webrtc}$

fitness app

web app for managing a mobile app that gives personalized nutrition, fitness and training to clients.

react · nextjs · styled-components · react-query

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth

April 26, 1989

Civil Status

Married

* References available upon Request